(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
アトリエ
Atelier
作詞作曲：渡辺翔
Lyrics & Composition: Sho Watanabe
保険言い訳ばら撒いて
Scattering insurance and excuses
横切った未来ぶれ途方に暮れないよう
So that the future I crossed doesn't blur and leave me at a loss
未知数が憧れに
As unknowns
絡まったって奪えはしない
get tangled with longings, they can't be stolen away
空を創ろう
Let's create the sky
散らかったパズル
A scattered puzzle
組み合わせても足りない
Even if combined, it's not enough
壁に写した
Projected on the wall
知らない世界の
of a world I didn't know
前にあった重い扉開け
Opening the heavy door that stood before
忘れてた少年の絵のように
Like the forgotten boy's drawing
温度は高く微熱まじりで夢はなしていたい
The temperature is high, with a slight fever, I want to keep dreaming
もう憧憬は描き飽きて
I'm already tired of drawing longings
全部を見るため開いたアトリエ
I opened the atelier to see everything
開いたアトリエ
Opened atelier
帰るアトリエ
Atelier to return to
いつかは
Someday
想像して書き殴って
Imagining and scribbling
塗り替えても外はもっと進んでいた
Even if I repaint, the world outside had advanced more
不揃いな景色の中
In the uneven scenery
棘が刺さっても走ってみたい
Even if thorns prick me, I want to try running
道を創ろう
Let's create a path
遠くなるほど
The further away it gets
細く薄れて描けない
it becomes thinner and fainter, and I can't draw it
イメージをした近い未来ぼやけたら
If the imagined near future becomes blurred
重い扉開け
Open the heavy door
その心大胆に染めよう
Let's dye that heart boldly
いつかの絵さえ霞むくらいの夢生み出したい
I want to create a dream that makes even past drawings fade
成果なんてわからない
I don't know the results
きっとそれでも去ったアトリエ
Surely, even so, I left the atelier
去ったアトリエ
The atelier I left behind
僕のアトリエ
My atelier
いつでも
Always
どれだけ濡れても
No matter how wet I get
擦ったって消えない
It won't disappear even if I rub it
戻せない
I can't go back
現実は鮮やか
Reality is vivid
忘れてた少年の絵のように
Like the painting of a boy I had forgotten
温度は高く微熱まじりで
The temperature is high, mixed with a slight fever
夢話していたい
I want to keep talking about dreams
もう憧憬は描き飽きて
I'm already tired of painting my longings
全部を見るため空いたアトリエ
An open atelier to see everything
空いたアトリエ
An open atelier
帰るアトリエ
The atelier I return to
いつかは
Someday
（息切れ）皆さーん、こんぬー！
(Panting) Hello everyone! Kon-nu!
ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアです！
I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen!
今日は私の生誕祭ライブ2024にお越しくださり、
Thank you all for coming
皆ありがとうございます！
to my Birthday Live 2024 today!
そんでもって、見てください、このステージ！
And look at this stage!
すっごい可愛いでしょー？
It's so cute, isn't it?
この日のために運営さんに作ってもらいました。
The staff built it just for this day.
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今日はこのステージでたくさん盛り上がっていくから、
We're going to have a lot of fun on this stage today,
一緒に皆で盛り上がろうぜ！
so let's all get hyped together!
そして今日はゲストもたくさんいるので、
And we have a lot of guests today,
ゲストの皆ともたくさん歌っちゃうよー！
so I'll be singing a lot with them too!
ハッシュタグはこちら、不知火フレア生誕祭2024で
The hashtag is here, so please post a lot using
たくさんポストしてね！
#ShiranuiFlareBirthdayLive2024!
それでは、今日は皆でたくさん盛り上がっていきましょう！
Now then, let's all have a blast today!
行くぞー！
Here we go!
ドクドクシテルコトバッカリ
Full of things that throb
サッパリシタイアジワウミライ
I want to refresh and taste the future
痛んだ小競り合いは
Hurting squabbles
伸び切った舌戦なんか
Like an overstretched war of words
飽きて匙を投げる
Getting tired and throwing in the towel
それや遠くに
Far away
巡り巡ってあなたのために掬う あぁ
Going round and round, scooping it up for you, ah
スプーンにでもなれたらいいな
I wish I could at least be a spoon
絵に描いたご馳走じゃないのに
Even though it's not a feast in a painting
フォンから作るソースじゃないのに
Nor a sauce made from stock
ちょっとばっかなぜでしょう 垂涎ものね
Why is it just a little bit mouth-watering?
色鮮やかなサラダボウルに 好き嫌いも笑って試して
In a colorful salad bowl, try your likes and dislikes with a laugh
案外好きになってるんじゃん
Turns out you've actually come to like it
鈍色の天気の日にには 厚い雲を裂いていくような
On dull-colored days, like tearing through thick clouds
風を見てみたい 魔法を見てみたい
I want to see the wind, I want to see magic
思いつく限りのレシピを眺めて
Looking at every recipe I can think of
振る舞おうぜ何回だって できたての料理を
Let's serve fresh dishes, over and over again
満開の笑みが見られたのなら
If I can see a full smile
創造の手間もどうだっていい
The effort of creation doesn't matter
知らない巡り合いは とんでもない未来
An unknown encounter is an unbelievable future
分け合えると知るんだ 不揃いな皿でも
I'll learn that we can share, even with mismatched plates
運命小さじ一杯 朝まで目一杯
A teaspoon of destiny, fully until morning
話そう大小と希望のプランを
Let's talk about large and small plans of hope
そうやって贅沢な匙を探していこう
That's how we'll search for the extravagant spoon
ぬくもりも まどろみも
The warmth, the slumber
今日の催促で 飛んでいく
Will fly away at today's urging
準備するから連れてって欲しいのさ
I'll get ready, so I want you to take me with you
朝日が良く見えるあの丘に
To that hill where you can see the sunrise clearly
レジャーシートの用意も ブランケットの装備も
Preparing the picnic mat, equipping the blanket
全てぱっぱと集めて揃ったよ
I gathered everything quickly, and it's all ready
思い付きのキャンピングへ
To an impromptu camping trip
誰でも巻き込み招待
Inviting and involving everyone
おもいっきり期待が空振ったとしても
Even if expectations completely miss the mark
理不尽ばっか襲ってきたって 言いたくなっても
Even if unreasonable things keep attacking and I want to complain
どうやったってダメな日もあるけど
There are days when nothing works no matter what
その失敗もスパイスなんだろう
But those failures must be the spice
初めての料理が どんなに苦くても
No matter how bitter the first dish is
誇らしく思うんだ 傷テープ貼った手で
I'll feel proud, with my hands covered in bandages
やりきった精一杯 後悔しない失敗
Having done my best, failures I won't regret
明日にはそう思えるのかな
I wonder if I'll feel that way tomorrow
まだまだ知らないことばっかり
Still so many things I don't know
ゆっくりといこう　満喫したい
Let's go slowly, I want to enjoy it to the fullest
単純に期待する好奇心
A simple curiosity looking forward to it
タップリと満たそうよ
Let's fill it up to the brim
隣に居たい
I want to be by your side
ささやかな気持ち込めて
With these modest feelings
少し怯えている不穏な夜は
On those unsettling nights when I'm a little scared
弱い心照らすような
Like something that shines on my weak heart
星を見ていたい
I want to see the stars
魔法を見てみたい
I want to see magic
思いつくだけのレシピを眺めて
Looking at all the recipes I can think of
振る舞おうぜ何回だってできたての料理を
Let's serve freshly made dishes, over and over again
満開の笑みが見られたのなら
If I could see a full-bloom smile
創造の手間もどうだっていい
Then the effort of creation doesn't matter
清濁混ぜ和えたとんでもない世界
A ridiculous world where good and evil are mixed
食べ尽くしていくんだ　酸いも甘いも全部
Let's eat it all up, both the sour and the sweet
熱いままにいっぱい　大好きをいっぱい
Full of heat, full of "I love you"s
詰めよう大層ご機嫌なメニューに
Let's pack them into a very cheerful menu
運命が小さじ一杯　朝まで目一杯
A teaspoon of fate, to the fullest until morning
話そう大小希望のプランを
Let's talk about our plans of hope, big and small
そうやって贅沢な匙を探していこう
That's how we'll search for the luxurious spoon
愚か（おろか）でいいのだろう　見渡す夢の跡
It's probably fine to be foolish, after surveying the ruins of dreams
さよなら蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
Shangri-La
作詞:atsuko ・ 作曲:atsuko / KATSU
Lyrics: atsuko ・ Composition: atsuko / KATSU
流れに身を任せ　いつか大人になってゆく
Surrendering to the flow, we eventually become adults
少しずつ汚れてゆくことなの
It's about getting a little dirty as we go
熟した果実だけ選ばれて
Only the ripened fruits are chosen
ナイフで裂かれて呑み込まれる前に
Before being split open by a knife and swallowed up
僕らは目指した　Shangri-La
We aimed for Shangri-La
欲望を抑えきれずに
Unable to restrain our desires
空想にまみれた自由を求め続けた
We continued to seek freedom covered in fantasies
今なら言えるだろう　ここが楽園さ
Now I can probably say it, this place is paradise
さよなら蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
大切な何かを　踏み台にしてまでも
Even if it meant using something precious as a stepping stone
一番高いリンゴ　掴みたかった
I wanted to grab the highest apple
無くしてから気付く尊いもの
Something precious that you only notice after losing it
幼い僕らは的はずれだらけさ
Our young selves were full of being off the mark
満ち足りた日々の制圧は
The suppression of those fulfilled days
情緒不安定になる
Makes one's emotions unstable
傷を負ってでも羽ばたきたいと願うよ
Even if I get hurt, I wish to take flight
愚か（おろか）でいいのだろう　見渡す夢の跡
It's probably fine to be foolish, after surveying the ruins of dreams
さよなら蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
輝く空は　無邪気さを装い
The shining sky, feigning innocence
全てを知っていた
Knew everything
Shangri-La...
欲望は抑えきれずに
Desires can't be suppressed
空想にまみれた
Covered in fantasies
自由を求め続けた
Continued to seek freedom
距離を置いてこそ
It's by keeping a distance
自分の大きさを知る
That you learn your own scale
未熟な心は
An immature heart
それさえわからないまま
Still doesn't even know that
今なら言えるだろう
Now I can probably say it
ここがShangri-La
This is Shangri-La
さよなら蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
どこまでも続くような青の季節は
The blue season that seems to go on forever
四つ並ぶ眼の先を遮るものは何もない
There's nothing to block what lies ahead of our eyes
アスファルト、蝉時雨を反射して
The asphalt reflects the chorus of cicadas
君という沈黙が聞こえなくなる
The silence that is you becomes inaudible
この日々が色褪せる、
These days fade,
僕と違う君の匂いを知ってしまっても
Even if I learn your scent that's different from mine
置き忘れてきた永遠の中に
In the eternity left behind
今でも青が棲んでいる
The blue still lives there even now
どんな祈りも言葉も、近づけるのに届かなかった
Prayers or words got closer but didn't reach
まるで静かな恋のような、頬を伝った夏のような色のなか
Like a quiet love, in a color like summer
君を呪う言葉がずっと喉の奥に仕えている
Words to curse you stay in the back of my throat
「また会えるよね」って
"We'll meet again, right?"
声にならない声
A voice that won't become a sound
昼下がり、地熱付く風の季節は
Early afternoon, the season of geothermal winds
想い馳せる、まだ何者でもなかった僕らの肖像
Recalling our portraits when we were nobodies
何もかも分かち合えたはずだったあの日から少しずつ
Bit by bit, since that day we shared everything
君と違う僕を呪うようになり代わっていく
I've changed, as if cursing the me unlike you
君の笑顔の奥の運命を
The fate behind your smile
見落としたこと、悔やみ尽くして
I regret overlooking it to the fullest
仇花と咲いて散っていく君に
To you, who blooms and scatters like a barren flower
さよなら
Goodbye
今でも青が棲んでいる
The blue still lives there even now
どんな祈りも言葉も、近づけるのに届かなかった
Prayers or words got closer but didn't reach
まるで静かな恋のような、頬を伝った夏のような色のなか
Like a quiet love, in a color like summer
君を呪う言葉がずっと喉の奥に仕えている
Words to curse you stay in the back of my throat
また会えるよねって
We'll meet again, right?
声にならない声
A voice that won't become a sound
無限に膨張しすぎた、
Infinitely expanded,
星の粒のように行方のない明日が零れた
Aimless tomorrow spilled over like stardust
超えてゆこう
Let's go beyond
君と...
With you...
希望に溢れた未来押し付けられている
A future full of hope is being forced upon us
燃え去った夢たちに
To the dreams that have burned away
心が動けない
My heart cannot move
それでも前進めという
Even so, it tells me to move forward
思いに導かれて
Guided by that feeling
踏み出したその先世界が
And beyond that step taken...
変わる
...the world changes
凍てつく氷を溶かせるものは
What can melt the freezing ice is...
熱く燃えさかる魂
...a fiercely burning soul
眠らせていた未だ見ぬ力呼び起こせ
Awaken the unseen power that has been dormant
大丈夫さ 繰り返しつぶやく言葉は力生み出す
It's okay; the words repeated over and over give birth to strength
底力にはまだ先がある
There's still more to your inner strength
突き抜けろ
Break through
心の全力は笑顔のため
All the heart's effort is for the sake of a smile
涙の向こう側超えて行ける 君と
Together with you, I can go beyond the other side of tears
正しさをまといながら
While wearing righteousness
言葉の群れたちが勇気か傷を広げる
Groups of words spread either courage or wounds
意識のないままに
Unconsciously
それでもそこに
Even so, if...
見えない愛見つけられたとしたら
...I could find an invisible love there
一粒の光が世界を変える
A single drop of light changes the world
深い愛を一瞬で姿を変えて
Changing the form of deep love in an instant...
恨みが牙をむく
...grudge bares its fangs
裏切りが産む彷徨う心抱きしめて
Embracing the wandering heart born from betrayal
培った勇気さえ些細な誤解だけで崩れ踏み出す
Even nurtured courage crumbles and steps out from just a minor misunderstanding
でも乗り越えて絆となれば揺らがない
But if we overcome it and it becomes a bond, it will not waver
後悔があるからまた歩ける
Because of regrets, I can walk again
雑音切り裂いて超えていこう 君と
Let's tear through the noise and go beyond, with you
凍てつく氷を溶かせるものは
What can melt the freezing ice is...
熱く燃えさかる魂
...a fiercely burning soul
眠らせていた未だ見ぬ力呼び起こせ
Awaken the unseen power that has been dormant
大丈夫さ 繰り返しつぶやく言葉は力生み出す
It's okay; the words repeated over and over give birth to strength
底力にはまだ先がある
There's still more to your inner strength
突き抜けろ
Break through
心の全力は笑顔のため
All the heart's effort is for the sake of a smile
涙の向こう側超えていける 君と
Together with you, I can go beyond the other side of tears
じっと日々を見逃さないで
Do not let the days pass you by
きっと大人忘れらしくするので
I will surely act like a forgotten adult
係り切りになるんだ
I'll be fully devoted
更新はまだ僕ら真珠の欠片だって
Updates are still pieces of pearls for us
価値どこにも物語がなければ
If there's no story of value anywhere
からくりの中で回る僕ら命だ
Our lives spinning inside a mechanism
奇跡のような毎日を
Days that are like miracles...
当たり前に手を差し伸べ合って過ごしている
We spend them naturally reaching out to each other
心温かであること笑うほど寂しいことはないでしょう
There's nothing lonelier than laughing about having a warm heart, is there?
落ち込む夜で咲いた色彩 気まぐれなように
The colors that bloomed on a depressed night, as if on a whim
どの人生も悪くはないだろう
Any life is probably not bad
強がることを知れど今までの足跡や生まれたことは消えやしない
Even if you know how to pretend to be strong, the footprints so far and the fact you were born won't disappear
軽い冗談で傷がついてしまう
Getting hurt by a light joke
柔らかなままでいてそのままのでいて
Stay soft, stay as you are
じっと日々を見逃さないで
Do not let the days pass you by
きっと大人忘れらしくするので
I will surely act like a forgotten adult
係り切りになるんだ
I'll be fully devoted
更新はまだ僕ら真珠の欠片だって
Updates are still pieces of pearls for us
価値そこに物語がなければ
If there's no story of value there
からくりのなかで　回る僕らは命だ
Within the clockwork, we who revolve are life itself.
おお　間違ってないね
Oh, it's not a mistake.
悲劇ばかりじゃここに立っていないってこと
If it were only tragedy, we wouldn't be standing here...
ああ
...ah.
気晴らしに今ならどこへだって
For a change of pace, we can go anywhere now.
光のように気が付かない
Not noticing, just like light.
間違ってる涙なんてない
There are no tears that are wrong.
じっと意味を見逃さないで
Don't let the meaning slip away.
きっと大人面らしくするので
Because I'll surely put on a grown-up face.
係りきりになるんだ
I'll be completely devoted.
感心はまだ僕ら　真珠の欠片だって無価値
Our admiration is still just fragments of pearls, worthless...
そこに物語がなければ
...if there's no story there.
からくりのなかで　回る僕らは命だ
Within the clockwork, we who revolve are life itself.
じっと意味を見逃さないで
Don't let the meaning slip away.
きっと大人面らしくするので
Because I'll surely put on a grown-up face.
係りきりになるんだ
I'll be completely devoted.
感心はまだ僕ら　真珠の欠片だって無価値
Our admiration is still just fragments of pearls, worthless...
そこに物語がなければ
...if there's no story there.
からくりのなかで　回る僕らは
Within the clockwork, we who revolve are...
なりそこないで溢れた
Brimming with failures.
挿し絵のような幸せを求めている
Seeking a happiness like an illustration.
感性は絵の具　混ざり合える
Sensibilities are like paints, they can blend together.
この街で当たり前に今　輝いてる
Shining naturally right now in this city.
ねえ
Hey.
気づいて
Notice it.
大事な人は誰？
Who is the important person?
虹が架かるまでの話
The Story Until a Rainbow Appears
青い風が吹いた
A blue wind blew.
二つ影が並んだ
Two shadows lined up.
不器用なほどにゆらゆら揺れてた
Swaying so clumsily.
意識しないことで
By not being conscious of it...
自分自身守っては
...you protect yourself.
いつの日か引いたラインを眺めて
Looking at the line you drew someday.
複雑に見せて
Making it look complicated...
単純な恋なのに
...even though it's a simple love.
答えが書かれたテスト　まだ解けないんだ
I still can't solve the test with the answer written on it.
嘘をついて誤魔化したって
Even if you lie and try to gloss it over...
心までは騙せない
...you can't deceive your heart.
このままでいいわけないよね
It's not okay to stay like this, right?
時は止まってくれないよ
Time won't stop for us.
素直になって見つめ合えば
If we become honest and look at each other...
今までの曇り空は青空へ
The cloudy sky until now will turn into a blue sky.
心と心結んだ虹が架かる
A rainbow connecting our hearts appears.
二人を包み込んで　輝くよ
It wraps around us and shines.
何気ないことがそう
Casual things, indeed...
かけがえのないものへ
...become irreplaceable.
変わるように二人の距離を縮めよう
Let's close the distance between us so they change.
深く深く呼吸して
Breathe deeply, deeply...
今日の空見つめて
...and look at today's sky.
流れ行く雲の切れ間を探した
I looked for a gap in the drifting clouds.
友達以上とか
Something more than friends...
恋人未満だとか
...or something less than lovers.
誰かが決めたルールを　飛び越えてみようよ
Let's try to jump over the rules someone else decided.
意識し合ってありのままで
Being conscious of each other, just as we are...
二人がもっと近づけば
...if we get closer...
隠し続けてた鼓動は　この空に響いてくよ
...our hidden heartbeats will resonate in this sky.
戸惑いだって切なさだって
Even the bewilderment, even the pain...
その全てがきっと大切なもの
...it's all surely something precious.
二人に目に見えない　形のない思いを
For us, invisible, formless feelings...
手繰り寄せればきっと　引き合うよ
...if we pull them close, they'll surely attract each other.
当たり前の帰り道
The usual path home
当たり前の連絡も
The usual messages too
突然なくなるかもしれない
Might suddenly disappear
そっと心に手を当て聞けばいい
Just gently place a hand on your heart and listen
きっと答えはひとつだから
Because I'm sure there's only one answer
ねぇ　気づいて
Hey, realize it
大事な人は誰？
Who is the important person?
嘘をついて誤魔化したって
Even if you lie and try to deceive
心までは騙せない
You can't fool your heart
眩しすぎるその光の中に
Within that light that's far too bright
二人が見えるよ
I can see the two of us
素直になって見つめ合えば
If we become honest and gaze at each other
今までの曇り空は
The cloudy skies we've had until now
青空へ
Turn into blue skies
心と心結んだ虹がかかる
A rainbow connecting heart to heart appears
二人を包み込んで
Enveloping the two of us
輝くよ
It will shine
はい！ということで
Alright! So,
前半が終了しましたけど
the first half has come to an end,
みんな盛り上がってる！？
is everyone having a great time!?
んー今回のセトリは前回よりも比較的新しい曲が多いなーなんて
Hmm, I wonder if you thought there were more relatively new songs in today's setlist
思った？
compared to last time?
ゲストとのお話とか、何でこの曲を選んだのかなーとかは
Talks with the guests, why I chose these songs, and things like that...
そんな感じのお話はまた後日ゆっくりお話しできたらいいなと思っております
I hope to have a chance to talk about those things in more detail at a later date.
この先も、みんなが知ってるあの曲やこの曲
From here on, there are still songs everyone knows,
ゲストもたくさんいるので、まだまだ一緒に盛り上がっていこうね！
and many more guests, so let's keep having fun together!
あ、ハッシュタグ #不知火フレア生誕祭2024 でも
Oh, and keep posting your photos and impressions
まだまだ写真や感想、どんどんポストしてくれるから嬉しいぞー！
with the hashtag #ShiranuiFlareSeitansai2024, it makes me so happy!
それでは、後半戦にいきましょう！
Now then, let's move on to the second half!
ゴーゴーゴーゴー！
Go, go, go, go!
春泥棒 作詞作曲：n-buna
Spring Thief / Composition & Lyrics: n-buna
高架橋を抜けたら
Once past the overpass,
雲の隙間に青が覗いた
a peek of blue appeared through the clouds.
最近どうも暑いから
Since it's been so hot lately,
ただ風が吹くのを待ってた
I was just waiting for the wind to blow.
木陰に座る
Sitting in the shade of a tree,
何か頬に付く
something brushes my cheek.
見上げれば頭上に咲いて散る
Looking up, flowers bloom and scatter overhead.
はらり、僕らもう息も忘れて
Gently fluttering down, we've already forgotten how to breathe,
瞬きさえ億劫
even blinking feels like too much effort.
さあ、今日さえ明日過去に変わる
Now, even today will become the past by tomorrow,
ただ風を待つ
just waiting for the wind.
だから僕らもう声も忘れて
And so, we've already forgotten our voices,
さよならさえ億劫
even saying goodbye feels like too much effort.
ただ花が降るだけ
Only the petals keep falling.
晴れり今、春吹雪
Clearing now, a spring blizzard.
次の日も待ち合わせ
Meeting up again the next day,
花見の客も少なくなった
the flower-viewing crowds have thinned.
春の匂いはもう止む
The scent of spring is already fading,
今年も夏が来るのか
wondering if summer will come again this year.
高架橋を抜けたら
Once past the overpass,
道の先に君が覗いた
I caught a glimpse of you at the end of the road.
残りはどれだけかな
I wonder how much time is left?
どれだけ春に会えるだろう
How many more springs will we be able to see?
川沿いの丘
On the hill along the river,
木陰に座る
sitting in the shade of a tree.
また昨日と変わらず今日も咲く
Still blooming today, just like yesterday.
花に、僕らもう息も忘れて 瞬きさえ億劫
At the flowers, we've even forgotten to breathe; even blinking is a chore.
花散らせ今 吹くこの嵐は まさに春泥棒
Scattering the flowers, this storm blowing now is truly a spring thief.
風に今日ももう 時が流れて 立つことさえ億劫
Today too, time flows in the wind; even standing is a chore.
花の隙間に空 散れりまだ 春吹雪
The sky between the flowers; still scattering, a spring blizzard.
今日も会いに行く
I'll go to see you today too.
木陰に座る
Sitting in the shade of a tree.
溜息を吐く
Letting out a sigh.
花ももう終わる
The flowers are ending soon.
明日も会いに行く
I'll go to see you tomorrow too.
春がもう終わる
Spring is ending soon.
名残るように時間が散っていく
Time scatters as if reluctant to leave.
愛を歌えば言葉足らず 踏む韻さえ億劫
If I sing of love, words aren't enough; even rhyming is a chore.
花開いた今を言葉如きが 語れるものか
How could mere words describe this moment of flowers blooming?
はらり、僕らもう 声も忘れて 瞬きさえ億劫
Gently, we've even forgotten our voices; even blinking is a chore.
花見は僕らだけ 散るなまだ 春吹雪
The flower viewing is just for us; don't scatter yet, spring blizzard.
あともう少しだけ
Just a little bit longer.
もう数えられるだけ
Only as many as can be counted now.
あと花二つだけ
Only two flowers left.
もう花一つだけ
Only one flower left.
ただ葉が残るだけ
Only leaves remain.
はらり今、春仕舞い
Gently now, spring comes to an end.
君が持ってきた漫画 くれた知らない名前の花
The manga you brought; the flowers with unknown names you gave me.
今日はまだ来ないかな 初めての感情知ってしまった
I wonder if it's still not coming today; I've learned of a feeling for the first time.
窓に飾った絵画なぞって 一人で宇宙を旅して
Tracing the painting displayed in the window, traveling through space alone.
それだけでいいはずだったのに
That should have been enough, but...
君の手を握ってしまったら
Once I've held your hand...
孤独を知らないこの街には
In this town that doesn't know loneliness...
もう二度と帰ってくることはできないのでしょう
We probably can never return again.
君が手を差し伸べた
You reached out your hand.
光で影が生まれる
Shadows are born from the light.
歌って聞かせてこの話の続き
Sing to me the continuation of this story.
連れて行って見たことない星まで
Take me away to a star I've never seen.
誰の手も声も届かない 高く聳え立った塔の上
Atop the tower standing tall, where no one's hand or voice can reach.
飛ばす風船葛 僕を君に笑ってほしいんだ
Letting fly balloon vines; I want you to smile at me.
満たされない穴を またせいのかいばや澄ましたポーズで
Filling the unfulfillable hole again with conversation or cool poses...
これまでを埋めてきたけど
...is how I've filled things up until now.
退屈な日々を蹴散らして
Kicking away the boring days.
君と二人でこの街中を泳げたらそれ
If the two of us could swim through this whole town, that...
…はどれだけ素敵なことでしょう
…is just how wonderful it is.
出したことないほど大きな
With a voice louder
声で今すぐ君に伝わる
than ever before, I'll reach you right now.
いびつな空気がきっとちょうど良くて
The distorted atmosphere must be just right.
世界の端と端を結んで
Connecting the edges of the world.
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって
Tracing the painting decorating the window,
一人で宇宙を旅して それだけでも不自由ないけど
and traveling the universe alone, I have no complaints with just that, but…
僕は選んでみたいの 高鳴る心 謎だらけの空を
I want to try choosing the throbbing heart and the sky full of mysteries.
安全なループを今書き換えて
Rewriting the safe loop right now.
君の手を握ってしまったら
Once I've grasped your hand,
孤独を知らないこの街にはもう二度と
to this city that knows no loneliness, I will never…
帰ってくることはできないのでしょう
…be able to return again.
いくらでも迷いながら
While getting lost as much as I want,
光も影も見に行こう
let's go see both the light and the shadows.
歌って聴かせて この話の続き
Sing it for me, the continuation of this story.
連れていってみたことない星まで
Take me to a star I've never seen before.
世界の端と端を結んで
Connecting the edges of the world.
It's only love
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If only one wish could come true,
君の側で眠らせて どんな場所でもいいよ
let me sleep by your side, anywhere will do.
Beautiful world 迷わず君だけを見つめている
Beautiful world, without hesitation, I'm only looking at you.
Beautiful boy 自分の美しさ まだ知らないの
Beautiful boy, you don't even know your own beauty yet.
It's only love
寝ても覚めても少年マンガ 夢見てばっか
Waking or sleeping, you're just dreaming of shonen manga.
自分が好きじゃないの
Don't you like yourself?
何が欲しいか分からなくて ただ欲しがって
Not knowing what you want, you just keep wanting.
ぬるい涙が頬を伝う
Lukewarm tears run down your cheeks.
言いたいことない ただもう一度会いたい
Nothing I want to say, I just want to see you once more.
言いたいこと言えない 根性なし かもしれない
I can't say what I want to, I might just be a coward.
それでいいけど もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
That's fine, but if only one wish could come true,
君の側で眠らせて どんな場所でもいいよ
let me sleep by your side, anywhere will do.
Beautiful world 迷わず君だけを見つめている
Beautiful world, without hesitation, I'm only looking at you.
Beautiful boy 自分の美しさ まだ知らないの
Beautiful boy, you don't even know your own beauty yet.
Beautiful World
どんなことでも
No matter what it is
やってみて
give it a try
損をしたって
even if you lose out
少し経験値
it adds a little more
あがる
to your experience
新聞はいらない
I don't need a newspaper
肝心なことが載ってない
the important things aren't in there
最近調子どうだい?
How have you been lately?
元気にしてるなら
If you're doing well
別にいいけど僕の世界
that's fine, but in my world
消えるまで
until it disappears
会えるなら
if we can meet
君のそばで眠らせて
let me sleep by your side
どんな場所でも結構
Any place is fine
Beautiful World
儚く過ぎてゆく君の中で
Inside of you, passing fleetingly
Beautiful World
気分は虚しく足りないね
I feel empty, it's not enough
もしも願い一つだけ
If I had just one wish
叶うなら
to come true
君のそばで眠らせて
let me sleep by your side
Beautiful World
Question 大胆に演じて
Question: perform boldly
Question 他愛のない人生
Question: a trivial life
Question 背反と安寧
Question: contradiction and peace
Question What? xxxxx
真っ二つだね世界は
The world is split in half
隠したそれぞれの正義は
The hidden justice of each
拮抗するがらんどう
An empty shell in conflict
ダマになり重なって
Becoming a lump, piling up
(Two-Sided Two-Face)
常識
Common sense
劣勢
Disadvantage
裏の裏
Inside out
最後も
The end too
最期も
The final hour too
関係ない
Doesn't matter
間一髪がスタンダード
By the skin of my teeth is standard
どうにかしてきたんだ
I've managed somehow
狂ったストーリー
A crazy story
全てが決まってたように
As if it were all decided
のべつ幕無しに異常事態
Incessant states of emergency
大抵わけもない
Usually for no reason at all
正しい間違いが不安定で
Right and wrong are unstable
裏返しの本音が溜まってゆく
Inside-out true feelings pile up
消化する術がないことも
Even the fact I have no way to digest them
気付かずに立ち向かうの?
Will I face them without noticing?
悲しくなどないけど
I'm not sad, but
こんなんじゃまだ100%は分からない
this way, I still don't understand 100%
もう不安など消してしまえたら良いと
If only I could erase all my anxiety
願って望んで憂い
Wishing, hoping, and sorrowing
そのカーテンが翻ったなら
If that curtain were to flutter
って理想と現実揺らぐんだ
My ideals and reality would waver
クラクラ
Dizzy
身一つで生き抜いた
Surviving with just my body
土砂降りに固まる不平不満
Complaints and dissatisfaction freezing in the downpour
逆行する世界もたまに味方となって
The backward world sometimes becomes an ally
(Two-Sided Two-Face)
正義で正義に抗うの?
Will you resist justice with justice?
サイコロ振っても平行線
Even if I roll the dice, it's a parallel line
どうしてなんで世界はドラマみたいに
Why, oh why, doesn't the world like a drama
うまくいかないのだろう
go well at all?
Question 大胆に演じて
Question: perform boldly
冴えないジョークで笑えたあの頃のように
Like those days when we could laugh at dull jokes
特別はいつも目の前にある
What's special is always right in front of us
大抵わけもない
Usually for no reason at all
日常
Daily life
寂しい言葉がフラッシュバックしてる
Lonely words are flashing back
泣いてしまえたら楽だったかな
Would it have been easier if I could just cry?
どっち付かずで嫌になるな
I hate being caught in between
守りたいものは何？
What is it I want to protect?
知らないことばっかだ こんなんじゃまだ
There's so much I don't know, like this,
1%にも満たない
it's not even 1%
って悩んで学んで繰り返し
I worry, I learn, I repeat
少しずつ見えてきた未来
Little by little, the future starts to appear
正しい間違いが不安定で
Correct mistakes are unstable
裏返しの本音が溜まってゆく
and my hidden feelings keep piling up
消化する術がないことも
Are you facing it without realizing
気付かずに立ち向かうの？
there's no way to process it?
悲しくなどないけど こんなんじゃまだ
I'm not sad, but like this, I still
100%は分からない
don't understand 100%
もう不安など消してしまえたら
I wish and hope that
良いと願って望んでる
I could just erase all my anxieties
そのカーテンが翻ったなら
If those curtains were to flutter,
って理想と現実揺らぐんだ
the ideal and reality would sway
クラクラ
Kurakura
(Question 大胆に演じて)
(Question Act boldly)
(Question 他愛のない人生)
(Question A trivial life)
(Question 背反と安寧)
(Question Antinomy and peace)
(Question What? x x x x x)
はい、みんな楽しんでますかー！
Hi, everyone, are you having fun?!
ついに残す曲はあと一曲となりましたが、
Finally, there's only one song left,
その前にここで一度、自分宣伝いいすか？
but before that, can I do a little self-promotion?
あ、なんかこの空気、新曲か？みたいな空気になっちゃうかなと思うんですけど、
Oh, I thought the atmosphere might turn into something like "Is it a new song?"
あの、大変恐縮なんですが、今回は…なんと！違います！
I'm very sorry, but this time... it's actually not!
やだー、まだ帰らないでー！
Wait, don't leave yet!
じゃあ、なんで今、宣伝なんや？ってとこなんですけど、
So, you might be wondering, "Why promote now?"
いや、なんていうか、まあ…
Well, how should I put it...
最後はエモい感じで終わらせたいんだもん！
I want to end on an emotional note!
ということで、お約束グッズ紹介！
So, as promised, merchandise introduction!
もちろん今年も出します！
Of course, I'm releasing them this year too!
不知火フレア 誕生日記念 2024
Shiranui Flare Birthday Celebration 2024
今年もみんなが喜ぶグッズを考えてみたからね！
I've thought of some merch that everyone will enjoy again this year!
まずはこちら！ おうちでまったりアクリルジオラマスタンド
First up is this! Relaxing at Home Acrylic Diorama Stand
イラストは、ちょん*先生に描いていただきました！ ありがとうございます！
The illustration was drawn by Chon-sensei! Thank you very much!
おうちで一緒にまったり過ごす雰囲気が可愛くてなごんじゃう。
The atmosphere of relaxing together at home is so cute and soothing.
君も一緒にゲームしない？
Want to play a game together?
続いてはこちら！ ランダムマルチバンド イラストは染宮うらは先生に書き下ろしていただきました！
Next is this! Random Multi-band. The illustrations were drawn by Somemiya Urara-sensei!
いつもありがとうございます！ 長くて気になるコードなんかを私がまとめちゃうぞ！
Thank you as always! I'll bundle up those long, annoying cords for you!
衣装も4種類、どの私も可愛すぎ！
There are 4 types of outfits, and I'm just too cute in all of them!
そして、フレアとおでかけぬいぐるみ おでかけ衣装ver.
And then, Go-out Plushie with Flare - Go-out Outfit ver.
「フレアもお外に連れてってー」なんちゃって
Hehe, "Take Flare outside too!"
少し小さめのぬいも欲しいなんて要望にお答えしてみました！ おでかけ衣装の可愛い私とおでかけしない？
I've answered the request for a smaller plushie! Want to go out with me in my cute outfit?
最後はこちら！ フレアとおそろいジャージ
Last but not least! Matching Jersey with Flare
「黒が着やすい」なんてみんなの意見に屈しました！
I gave in to everyone's opinion that "black is easy to wear"!
ふふ、黒もいいじゃん。 私とおそろいで、ちょっとそこのコンビニまでデートしない？
Hehe, black is nice too. Want to go on a date to the convenience store around the corner in our matching jerseys?
ワンポイントで隠れ推しアピールも可愛いぞ！
The small accent to subtly show your support is cute too!
フルセット購入はこちら！ めちゃくちゃ可愛いちょん先生描き下ろしポストカードがついてくるよ！
Click here for the full set! It comes with an incredibly cute postcard drawn by Chon-sensei!
そして今回も書きます！ 数量限定、直筆サイン入りメッセージ！
And I'll be doing it again this time! Limited quantity, hand-signed message!
数量限定だけど、いつもよりかなり量増やしたので、 焦らず、慌てず、みんなの手に渡るかも。
It's limited quantity, but I've increased the amount quite a bit, so if you don't panic, it might reach everyone's hands.
複製メッセージの方も、今回も少しだけ長めに書くから、 万が一買えなかったって人も悲しまないでね。
I'll also write the printed messages a bit longer this time, so don't be sad even if you couldn't get one.
改めて、今日はみんな来てくれて、ありがとうございました。
Once again, thank you all for coming today.
ついに最後の曲となりました。
It's finally time for the last song.
君たちに出会えて本当によかった。
I'm so glad I could meet you all.
みんな大好きだよ！
I love you all!
遠くで
In the distance
揺れてる稲穂の海
A sea of swaying ears of rice
ほおあげ...
Lifting my face...
...目指した思い出と
...with the memories I aimed for
僕らは今日までの
We've remembered...
悲しいこと全部覚えてるか
...everything sad until today
忘れたか
Have you forgotten it?
小さな手にもいつからか僕らを追い越してゆく強さ
In those small hands, there's a strength that will eventually surpass us
熟れた葡萄の下泣いてた日から歩いた
Walking from the day we cried under the ripened grapes
小さな手でも離れても僕らはこの道ゆくんだ
Even with small hands, even if we're apart, we'll walk this road
いつかくる日は一番の思い出をしまって
Saving our best memories for the day that will eventually come
季節は移り
The seasons change
もう冷たい風が
And already a cold wind...
包まれて眠れ
...is wrapping us to sleep
あの春の歌の中で
Within that spring song
小さな手にもいつからか僕らを追い越してゆく強さ
In those small hands, there's a strength that will eventually surpass us
濡れた頬にはどれだけの笑顔が映った
How many smiles were reflected on those wet cheeks?
小さな手でも離れても僕らはこの道ゆくんだ
Even with small hands, even if we're apart, we'll walk this road
そしてくる日は僕らも思い出をしまった
And on the day that comes, we've saved our memories, too
小さな手でもいつの日か僕らを追い越してゆくんだ
Even with small hands, one day they'll surpass us
やがてくる日は新しい季節を開いた
The day that eventually comes has opened a new season